<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Grassy Medium</title>
    <description>A personal blog about technology, design and stuffs.
</description>
    <link>http://www.uxjulia.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.uxjulia.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 16:53:48 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 16:53:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clamcase Pro for iPad Mini</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I did it. I went and bought the Clamcase Pro for iPad Mini. I had been looking at it for the past few days. Maybe it was only a day... Whatever, it felt like days. And, of course, the cookies in my browser allowed Clamcase to target ads towards me from that point on, never letting me forget that I once contemplated their product for purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to stay away, researching alternatives and asking myself, &amp;quot;Do I truly need a keyboard that costs 1/3 of the price of the device it is attaching itself to?&amp;quot;I tried to stay away, but the beautifully designed keyboard, high-res product photos and those damn targeted ads just kept pulling me back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the Clamcase website offered me a coupon code for signing up for their newsletter, which would bring down the cost by $20. The temptation to purchase had never been higher. I decided to look up some video reviews to see how it looks in motion and to get a better size comparison. Or perhaps I just wanted a little bit more of a nudge to convince myself that I should buy it. In any case, after a few videos I decided to go for it. If I&amp;#39;m gonna get another keyboard, I&amp;#39;m gonna get one of the best ones out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now await its arrival, which should be within the next 3-5 days. Today though, another keyboard splurge of mine arrives. The CODE Mechanical Keyboard. I don&amp;#39;t know how it happened, but suddenly I&amp;#39;m a keyboard enthusiast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.uxjulia.com/2015/04/06/Clamcase-Pro-for-iPad-Mini.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.uxjulia.com/2015/04/06/Clamcase-Pro-for-iPad-Mini.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
