<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>THE CRUMPLED LOGARITHM</title>
    <description>Personal ramblings about technology, gadgets and experience design.
</description>
    <link>http://www.uxjulia.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.uxjulia.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 21:48:06 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 21:48:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Apple Watch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So the first batch of Apple Watches were shipped out this week and I just got mine today. I promptly put it on, adjusted the settings and installed my apps that have a Watch counterpart. For the most part, the size of the Watch makes many apps pretty useless in my opinion. The only apps that truly seem to have any use are the reference apps like weather, calendar or apps that allow remote control like Apple Remote, music control&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;www.knocktounlock.com&quot;&gt;Knock&lt;/a&gt;. Everything else is just too difficult to really be useful on such a tiny screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only had the watch for a few hours now but I can list a few things so far that I like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heartbeat monitor&lt;/strong&gt;: I’ve always wanted an activity monitor that had a built in heartbeat monitor, and now I have one!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raised wrist detection&lt;/strong&gt;: The motion sensor has been working flawlessly to display the watch face when I raise my wrist.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPhone Camera control functionality&lt;/strong&gt;: There is pretty visible latency between the watch and iPhone’s camera display, but this will come in handy as a remote should the need ever arise. Hopefully a software update in the future will improve this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple TV Remote&lt;/strong&gt; This will certainly come in handy when I’m too lazy to get up to find the actual remote. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sport band&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve had way more activity monitors that came with a similar “sport” band, but none are as luxurious as Apple’s. I have fairly small wrists but this band fits me perfectly, with a couple of notches left over. I also really like how the end of the band tucks in so that it won’t catch onto anything when you’re out doing sporty things with your sport band. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Why hasn’t Spotify released an Apple Watch app yet? &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 17:26:52 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.uxjulia.com/2015/04/24/The-Apple-Watch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.uxjulia.com/2015/04/24/The-Apple-Watch.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Version Control With Draftin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m frequently asked to proofread people’s writing, whether it be a resume, an essay or an email. While there is software out there that comes with change tracking, they don’t incorporate it with version control and collaboration in a way that’s easy to use and straightforward enough for the less than tech-savvy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while back, I had scoured the internet for a “GitHub” for writers. Basically a tool that would give me version control, allow multiple people to collaborate at once, easily distinguish any changes that were made and subsequently reject or accept those changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution that I found was in the form of a website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.draftin.com&quot;&gt;draftin.com&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a barebones site with very little fluff and gets right to the point. You can start your writing project right there, or paste in writing from an outside source. It keeps track of all your changes and allows you to share your writing for feedback or, like in my case, share the edits you’ve made to someone else’s writing. It’s completely free to use but if you like the service, you can donate by buying a monthly or yearly subscription to help maintain the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing is that all of the change tracking features work even if everything was done outside of the website. For example, I had already made all my edits to an essay but wanted to be able to share exactly where those edits were with another person. So I pasted in the original text into DraftIn and saved that as a draft. Then I went in and pasted over all of that text with my edited text. When I share the link, it highlights all of my changes right alongside the original text with an option to accept or reject. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.uxjulia.com/websites/2015/04/19/Version-Control-With-Draftin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.uxjulia.com/websites/2015/04/19/Version-Control-With-Draftin.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>websites</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clamcase Pro for iPad Mini</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So I did it. I went and bought the Clamcase Pro for iPad Mini. I had been looking at it for the past few days. Maybe it was only a day… Whatever, it felt like days. And, of course, the cookies in my browser allowed Clamcase to target ads towards me from that point on, never letting me forget that I once contemplated their product for purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to stay away, researching alternatives and asking myself, “Do I truly need a keyboard that costs 1/3 of the price of the device it is attaching itself to?”I tried to stay away, but the beautifully designed keyboard, high-res product photos and those damn targeted ads just kept pulling me back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the Clamcase website offered me a coupon code for signing up for their newsletter, which would bring down the cost by $20. The temptation to purchase had never been higher. I decided to look up some video reviews to see how it looks in motion and to get a better size comparison. Or perhaps I just wanted a little bit more of a nudge to convince myself that I should buy it. In any case, after a few videos I decided to go for it. If I’m gonna get another keyboard, I’m gonna get one of the best ones out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now await its arrival, which should be within the next 3-5 days. Today though, another keyboard splurge of mine arrives. The CODE Mechanical Keyboard. I don’t know how it happened, but suddenly I’m a keyboard enthusiast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.uxjulia.com/gadgets/2015/04/06/Clamcase-Pro-for-iPad-Mini.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.uxjulia.com/gadgets/2015/04/06/Clamcase-Pro-for-iPad-Mini.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>gadgets</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
